

Henok Tsegaye

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Henok is a software engineer with four years of experience developing professional software. He shows strong expertise in working with TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS3, and ECMAScript (ES6). Henok's created numerous React projects, used Linux and DevOps to deploy applications, and integrated CI/CD pipelines. His projects include refactoring old class-based components, architectural and structural designs for frontend applications, and translating designs to React components with functionalities

EMPLOYMENT



Front-end React Developer Captario AB

Captario develops SUM® – Strategic Uncertainty Management, a cloud-based modeling & simulation software further empowered by Al. Jan 2022 to Sept 2022 (9 months)

- Collaborated closely with the UI/UX team to develop new UI designs of new features and functionalities according to the design provided by the team.
- Helped finish the transition to a new UI/UX design in different parts of the application.
- Tracked and fixed bugs on the front-end part of the application to boost productivity.

200

Senior Full-stack Developer Elnet Technologies

July 2021 to Jan 2022 (6 months)

- Designed and developed referral features for an existing application that the company was already using.
- Refactored and introduced an improved code structure and way of working with the existing code for better maintainability.
- Helped track and resolve bugs and issues with the existing code.

← henoktsegaye.com

in <u>LinkedIn</u>

maxhenock@gmail.com

+251946235219

SKILLS

| React.JS | Next.js | Redux |
|------------|---------|------------|
| Typescript | SQL | Javascript |
| Express.JS | Nest.JS | MongoDB |

EDUCATION HISTORY

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Addis Ababa University - Addis Ababa,

Ethiopia - 2014 to 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

React, Ranking in the Top 10%

TestDom From 2021 to present



Senior Full-stack Engineer Addis Software

A software development company that works closely with Ethiopian & Swedish developers from Sweetopia. Sept 2021 to Jul 2021 (9 months)

- Led a team of three software engineers delegating tasks to both front-end and back-end developers. Made technical decisions for different parts of the application considering maximum productivity.
- Interviewed more than 35 prospective employees. Mentored junior software developers on the team and helped them with new technologies and the company's way of working.
- Collaborated closely with the product and business managers to decide on the application's features from a UI/UX and development standpoint.
- Implemented React components and Redux store with Redux-saga for asynchronous workflow for the application's front end.
- Used Node.js to scrap content from different platforms using background jobs that can be aggregated and visualized for data visualization and invoice tracking.
- Made websites optimized for search engine optimization (SEO) with low cumulative layout shift (CLS), high SEO scores with asset caching, and image optimization, enabling the customer to achieve 50% more traffic.

Full-stack Developer

Sept 2019 to Jan 2021

- Developed an application for dog walkers with React, Redux, and Node.js. The application uses WebSocket to allow dog walkers to chat with dog owners.
- Tracked and fixed bugs with WordPress websites according to the design the clients provided.
- Made WordPress themes and plugins for a custom design according to the client's needs.

Junior Full-stack Software Engineer ETTA Solutions

Jan 2019 to Sept 2019

- Developed an admin panel for managing complaints sent by mobile phone applications along with a map view of where the complaints were issued. Used React, Redux, Material-UI, and Redux Thunk to develop the admin panel.
- Identified the project's requirements along with the project manager and the tech lead to better understand what was required and how it should be implemented.
- Presented a demo of an admin panel on behalf of the company and secured cooperation with Addis Ababa City Administration Traffic Management Agency.

Full-stack Developer Freelance

July 2018 to Jan 2019

- Developed an app that manages USSD messages and sends SMS messages in bulk to USSD subscribers. Made the application with PHP, Laravel, and JavaScript.
- Built a website for the Ethiopian Statistical Association for which it is possible to submit research papers and conference registrations.
- Made an internship management system for companies to post and interns to apply to internship programs.

EXPERIENCE

Affiliate Revenue Tracking and Management System Addis Software

Oversaw a team of three developers creating an affiliate revenue tracking and management system that works by scraping affiliate programs daily and monthly and aggregating the data to show relevant information. It can communicate with 12 affiliate programs that do not have API by logging in, scraping, and sending an invoice for scraped content.

We developed the API using Node.js, the front end with TypeScript, React, Redux, Redux-saga, and Ant Design, and for the scraper, we used a cron job written using Node.js. The cron job reports' failed attempts give notifications. This project also uses GitLab CI/CD and deploys the changes on the server set up on DigitalOcean. The Docker and Docker Compose were set up to run multiple Docker instances on both staging and production environments for the back and front ends.

Zemach FM

https://zemachfm.com/

Zemach FM is a complete application with a website for hosting podcasts. The website's co-host and I have collaboratively made this highly maintainable and multi-lingual website that supports dark and light themes. The website uses React, Redux, Redux-saga, JavaScript, TypeScript, and Next.js. We have used WordPress for providing and writing our custom API.

This website has changed the way the audience of Zemach FM listens to podcasts. The audience has shifted from other apps to the new website, and the podcasts have received positive feedback from the audience.

All-in Global Addis Software

https://all-in.global

All-in Global is a website for a language translation and localization company. I developed the project using Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, CSS, PHP, and WordPress according to the company's predefined design. The project has a CI/CD for the staging environment, and I used DigitalOcean to deploy it. After deploying the website, the company started scoring on predefined keywords on Google and increasing its revenue.

Fruity Slots

Addis Software

https://fruityslots.com

Fruity Slots is a WordPress SEO-driven website with a developed theme. I made this website for a company under Addis Software to score on search engines. I created a content management system (CMS) for seven items that the website managed using WordPress and ACF plugins. Custom plugins were added for bulk page creation using comma-separated values (CSV) upload and MySQL for data storage. I implemented rich results for search engines and gave generalized content data. The front end was developed using customized Bootstrap, Sass, and custom CSS, and it employed jQuery, JavaScript, and Vue.js. Finally, I created a CI/CD solution for the staging to see the changes before merging the staging into production developed using Nginx.

The company scored on search engines with keywords and expanded its reviewed items.